Prologue: Heritage Clues

Less than a week after he left the spirit folk village, Rio reached the Yagumo region.

It would have been a harsh, two to three month journey on foot — even if he had enhanced his body with spirit arts — but thanks to the wind spirit arts he had learned from the village, he was able to fly the whole way instead. Therefore, he was able to make his journey from the village to Yagumo with relative ease. From that moment on, however, Rio’s troubles truly began.

Visiting the Yagumo region to mourn his late parents in their own homeland was understandable, but Rio had almost no information that he’d need to pinpoint the location of their place of birth. The only information he had were their names.

There were over 30 countries of various sizes within the Yagumo region, making his attempt to locate their hometown in this way seem almost futile.

That did not, however, discourage Rio from moving ahead with achieving his goal. He visited all the cities and villages in the western side of Yagumo, with the hopes that he’d find someone who recognized his parents’ names.

But having the will didn’t necessarily mean there was a way...

Several months passed with no leads.

At present, Rio was visiting the Kingdom of Karasuki, a large nation located in the western area of the Yagumo region. He had already passed through several cities and villages, and was about to head off toward the next village, so he used his wind spirit arts to take to the air. His destination was a small dot on the horizon.

...That village, huh?

With a birds’ eye view, he could make out roads stretching out from the east and west sides of the village, a small hill to the north, and an overgrown mountain covered in trees to the south.

It was your typical, idyllic village; unremarkable at best.

The residential area occupied the center of the village, where houses made of wood, lime, and clay stood in rows. Judging by their numbers, the population was probably around three hundred or so. Surrounding the center were fields and pastures, where villagers could be spotted working.

They said that Yuba, the chief of this village, has lots of connections. Rio recalled the information he had gathered from the chief of a neighboring village he had previously visited.

To be honest, he didn’t really expect to find much here. At this point, he couldn’t even recall how many times he’d gotten his hopes up, only to be disappointed once again... But he wasn’t about to give in to his despair.

To avoid making an unnecessary commotion by landing right in the middle of the village, Rio made his descent a reasonable distance away. After touching down on the road leading from the west side of the village, he lightly jogged toward the entrance.

The village was surrounded by a simple wooden fence, with no lookouts stationed at the entrance, allowing Rio to walk in freely.

Even so, there were villagers working on their farms in every direction, so they were aware of the fact that someone had walked in from the outside. Sure enough, as Rio arrived at the entrance of the village, several of the villagers looked up at him.

However, none of them approached — they just watched him from a distance.

The atmosphere nearly made him hesitate from going any further, but any village would be wary of unknown outsiders. This was normal, and it was a reaction that Rio had become very familiar with.

Rio bowed briefly at the farmers, before stepping through the entrance. He calmly walked straight toward the center of the village — where the chief’s house was most likely to be located — so that he could finish his business here quickly.

Two girls dressed in simple clothing appeared from the field beside him, and hesitantly approached. They seemed to be in their teens; one of them looked about two to three years older than the other.

“Umm, did you need something from our village?” The older looking girl asked Rio timidly.

“Hello. My name is Rio,” Rio replied in a formal tone and gave them a friendly smile. “I’m on a journey to search for someone. I’d like to meet the chief of this village... Would they happen to be present at the moment?” he tacked on his question.

His pronunciation was slightly awkward, but he was fluent enough to have no trouble speaking in conversation, thanks to extensive knowledge of Ursula and the others in the spirit folk village. They had taught him the language used in the Yagumo region during their time together. His many months spent wandering through Yagumo also helped.

Rio introduced himself politely and explained his situation, causing the two girls to widen their eyes.

“A-Ah, umm, h-hello. P-Pleased to make your, umm, acquaintance? Are you a traveler? The village chief is in... is... present? Shall I show you the way?” The older girl offered nervously. She didn’t seem very comfortable speaking formally.

“Thank you very much. Many people tend to be wary of outsiders suddenly appearing at their door... If it wouldn’t be an inconvenience, I gladly accept your offer,” Rio thanked her in a calm voice, bowing his head and smiling faintly.

“S-Sure! Then... Umm... Follow me, please!” The older girl nodded with a shrill voice and began to walk toward the center of the village. Meanwhile, the younger girl, who had been standing behind her, stared at Rio’s face in a daze.

“...Is something the matter?” Rio stopped in confusion just as he was about to follow the older girl who had already walked away.

“...Huh? Ah, n-no! I-It’s, umm... it’s nothing!” The younger girl blushed and shook her head furiously.

“What are you doing, Sayo? Come along, now.”

“O-Okay, Ruri!”

Prompted by the older girl named Ruri, Sayo — the younger girl — hurriedly broke out into a run. Rio tilted his head slightly before he set off after them.

The two girls still seemed to be nervous as they walked uncomfortably, all the while shooting looks over their shoulder at Rio on occasion. Sayo, especially, glanced at him quite often.

Are outsiders really that rare? Rio thought, staring at Sayo’s back as they walked.

The three of them maintained that awkward silence and distance until they arrived at the village chief’s house.

“Granny, you have a guest! He says he’s looking for someone!” Ruri yelled loudly as she entered the house. The front door opened to a clay floor that led to an elevated living room, where a sunken fireplace was set up to warm the area.

“You don’t need to be so loud, Ruri. I can hear you perfectly fine... Oh?”

After a moment, an old woman appeared. She spotted Rio standing behind Ruri and Sayo in the entrance and narrowed her eyes.

“Hello — it’s nice to meet you. My name is Rio. I have come today to ask you a few things, village chief,” Rio introduced himself cordially and took a step forward. The old woman widened her eyes.

“Oho, what a polite one we have here. Your clothes are unfamiliar and you have a slight accent... A traveler from a foreign country, perhaps?” The old woman’s gaze analyzed Rio, as though she was trying to identify his origins.

“Yes, I am not from here. I have been traveling through many different countries.”

“I see, I see. ...Ah, forgive me. My name is Yuba. I am sure you are aware of this already, but I am the chief of this village.”

“Pleased to make your acquaintance.” Rio bowed.

“Yes yes, enough of the formalities. Please, do come inside. Ruri, Sayo, go pour some tea.”

“Okay! Let’s go, Sayo,” Ruri replied energetically to Yuba’s order. Sayo nodded awkwardly before heading to the kitchen with her.

“You. Come up to the living room. ...Oof.” Yuba directed Rio to one of the seating cushions before the sunken fireplace and sat down.

“Excuse me.” Rio gave a simple bow before taking off his shoes and stepping up to the living room. Then, he removed the hooded overcoat he had been wearing over the sword and armor he had received from the spirit folk, and placed them on the floor along with his sheathed sword.

“...Those clothes you are wearing under your overcoat are rarely seen in this area. That sword is splendid, but the shape is rather odd. You definitely don’t seem like someone from this country.” Yuba was gazing at his appearance curiously, just as Rio had expected she would.

“Neither my weapons nor my attire were made in this country. I normally wear an overcoat to avoid drawing attention to them.”

“True, your appearance does attract the eye. Not to mention how high quality your equipment is, especially for an average traveler.”

“Yes, these items are excellent. A craftsman I am greatly indebted to made them for me as a special gift.”

“...Is that so. Well, I won’t pry any further than that. The tea is ready now, so let me hear your story.”

Ruri and Sayo were bringing the tea over precisely at that moment, so Yuba cut off the conversation there. The girls split up to each serve Yuba and Rio the tea.

“Thank you very much.” Rio thanked Sayo, as she was the one who left the tea in front of him.

Shaking her head in embarrassment, Sayo retreated to the corner of the room. Her behavior made Ruri smile in amusement. Rio had been wondering about Sayo’s strange behavior for a while now, but tried to put that aside as he began to speak.

“I am searching for someone who knew of my parents when they were alive. The reason I am visiting this village is because I have heard that Lady Yuba has the most extensive connections of those who live in this area.”

“Hm, I see...” Yuba gave a small nod of understanding, before prompting him to keep talking.

“I believe my mother and father lived in the Yagumo region around fifteen years ago, but I am not sure of the details... Have you ever heard the names Zen and Ayame before, Lady Yuba?” Rio said, naming his parents.

“...Did you just say... Zen... and Ayame...?” Yuba’s eyes widened, the arm that had extended to grab her teacup completely frozen. Her head shot up as she carefully fixed her gaze on Rio’s face.

She definitely seemed to know something; her reaction clearly displayed that. Even Rio’s typically calm demeanor disintegrated as his eyes widened, too.

“Ah, no. I’ll have to hear more about them first,” Yuba hesitated, before giving a vague reply and looking to the girls. “Ruri, Sayo — our discussion may go on longer than expected. You two can return to your work,” she ordered.

“Eeeh... But why?” Ruri pouted her lips unhappily.

“Go on, now. Don’t poke your nose into other people’s personal business. Make sure you keep your lips sealed around the other villagers, too.”

“Okaaay. Tch. And it seemed kind of interesting too... Let’s go, Sayo.” At Yuba’s strict and unyielding words, Ruri reluctantly backed down.

“Y-Yeah.”

After Ruri and Sayo left the house, Yuba looked at Rio and slowly began to speak. “Now, could you give me more details about your parents’ features and characteristics? They may just be someone I know.”

“Sure, of course...” Rio concealed his wavering emotions with a nod, then calmly began to recount their history.

His parents had been born in the Yagumo region. When they were young, they had spent years on a long journey to migrate to the Strahl region. After that, they wandered for a while until Rio was born, and they settled down in the Kingdom of Beltrum. However, Rio’s father Zen died before Rio was old enough to know him. After that, he lived alone with his mother Ayame.

Rio also explained Ayame’s personality and what kind of mother she was, with Yuba listening intently to every one of Rio’s words.

“...After that, when I was still young, my mother passed away, too...” Rio’s expression darkened a bit as he spoke about his mother’s death. He didn’t offer any specifics to how she had died; he didn’t want to remember it, and he didn’t want to speak of it.

To be honest, he still hadn’t organized his thoughts about what had happened.

“Thank you for telling me. I must have made you recall some difficult memories... But there’s no mistaking it. Those two are definitely the same people I know. In fact, if I look carefully, I can see some of their features in your face. Dear me, old age really does no favors. Hmm, no... Perhaps you could say that it was this old age of mine that allowed us to meet,” Yuba said with a somewhat helpless and regretful expression.

“...If you don’t mind me asking, how did my parents know you...?” Rio asked fearfully, desperately keeping his voice from wavering.

“I am Zen’s mother, and your grandmother. It is nice to finally meet you,” Yuba answered, smiling rather awkwardly.

“You’re my father’s... Ah, umm. It’s nice to meet you too.” Rio stared at Yuba’s face blankly for a moment, before bowing his head uncomfortably. Yuba seemed to recognize her next question as being a difficult one, but she couldn’t help but ask it anyway.

“...I’m sorry, but could you tell me a little more? I’d like to hear about your reason for coming to this land from so far away, just to search for information about those two. The effort you’ve put in, and the hardships you have gone through to reach here, must be far beyond my imagination.”

Rio hesitated for a few moments before answering. “...I wanted to make a grave. I don’t have any remains or mementos, but I wanted to mourn them in their own homeland. And mom... my mother had promised to take me to her hometown some day. She passed away before we could make that happen, but I wanted to try to make it to this land myself,” he answered carefully.

“I see. You did well to make it here. However, the truth is... How should I put this? Their graves already exist,” Yuba said with a hint of reluctance.

“Their graves... already exist? But didn’t they leave this land alive?” Rio unintentionally asked out loud, taken by surprise.

“Yes, that’s correct. But their graves exist. Judging by your reaction, it seems you are unaware of their reasons for abandoning their homeland. Is that right?” Yuba asked while peering at Rio’s face.

“Yes, that is true. Does that mean you know why, Lady Yuba?” Rio asked in return.

“Indeed, I know the reason. However, you’ll have to forgive me, as I cannot tell you the details myself.” Yuba shook her head with an apologetic look.

“May I ask why...?”

“Certain circumstances drove the two of them to leave this country in secret. Since there was no chance that they’d return, those who knew the truth constructed graves for them on the hill. That is all I can tell you right now,” Yuba replied, selecting her words carefully.

“They left this country... in secret...”

“For now, I will lead you to their graves. Would you like to hold a memorial service for them?” Yuba offered to a contemplative Rio.

“...Yes, of course. Please allow me to do that.”

To be honest, there was still a lot that was left unclear, but there was no point in Rio pondering over it any more than this. If Yuba had no intention of answering him, then he wasn’t about to force her to. Rio decided to focus on the matter of his parents’ graves first.

◇◇◇

Afterward, Yuba led Rio to the small hill a little ways north of the village. The top of the hill offered a sweeping view of the village below and the mountains surrounding it, making the scenery quite beautiful.

Two stone pillars stood before that backdrop. They had been maintained very well, as they were neat and tidy, with no signs of wind erosion.

“These are their graves. Their names aren’t carved on them, but they’re filled with their keepsakes,” Yuba said as she stood before the stone pillars.

“...I see.” Rio nodded vaguely, his eyes fixed on the stone pillars.

“...Perhaps I can tell you what happened to your parents when the time comes,” Yuba said slowly as she looked at Rio. Rio’s eyes widened, and he stared back at her.

“Would you consider staying in this village until that time comes?” Yuba asked, her expression filled with affection.

“...Would that be all right?” Rio questioned worriedly.

“You are my grandson. There’s no need for a grandchild to act modest around his grandmother,” Yuba replied with a bright smile on her face.

“Grandchild... Grandmother...” Rio muttered the words, as though he was mulling over them.

“There are more than enough spare rooms. My relatives have all died from war and sickness, so it’s just me and Ruri right now. She’s the older girl who led you to my home,” Yuba explained as Rio stood there in silence.

“And Ruri, is she...?”

“She’s the daughter of Zen’s older brother, which makes her your cousin. She’s fifteen right now.”

“I see. That makes her one year older than me.”

“...I’m surprised to hear you’re so young. While your face is still childish, your personality is so mature that I mistook you for being older.”

“That’s not true.” Rio finally cracked a faint smile and shook his head. That made Yuba give a huff of laughter.

“Is that so? Well, that’s that. Can I take that as a yes to my offer?”

“Yes. I will be in your care,” Rio said hesitantly, bowing his head at Yuba.

“It would be my pleasure to have you with me. I know it may be difficult to adjust immediately, but there’s no need to be so stiff. Relax, and be at ease,” Yuba said with a small shrug.

“Okay... Yuba.”

Rio decided to simply call her by her name, instead of “Lady Yuba.” When he thought about the fact she was his real grandmother, he found it easier to call her that.

“Fufu. Oh, speaking of which... Is it all right if we hide the truth of your heritage from the rest of the villagers?” Yuba asked with a cheerful grin.

“Of course, that would be fine,” Rio agreed, picking up on the implication behind Yuba’s words. They couldn’t reveal Rio’s origins to the village because of the circumstances that had caused Zen and Ayame to leave the country. It was possible — no, it was almost certain — that there would be people in this village that had known them.

“I’m sorry for the inconvenience. We can decide on the rest of the details at the house. I’m going to head back now... Would you like to stay here a little longer?” Yuba asked out of consideration for Rio.

“Yes, please.”

“Do you know the way back?”

“I’ll be fine.”

“Oh? Then make sure you come back before the sun sets. We’ll host a welcome party for you, though it will be a small one.” With that, Yuba turned on her heel and left.

“Thank you for your hospitality,” Rio said, bowing deeply toward Yuba’s retreating back. Once Yuba’s figure had disappeared from view, he raised his head to the stone pillars.

“...I guess that means I’ll be staying at your place for a while, dad. It still hasn’t quite sunk in that I have relatives other than the two of you, though...” Rio muttered toward the pillars, a trace of bewilderment in the smile that pulled at his lips. Of course, there was no response.

After a while, he turned around to look at the village. He spent another hour or so on the hill in sombre silence, before making his way back to the village chief’s house just before the sun set.

“Excuse me,” Rio said as he hesitantly walked through the open front door. There, Yuba was waiting along with Ruri, who had finished her work.

“Welcome back,” they said.

“...Thank you.” Rio was taken aback, but he managed to shyly return their greeting.

Then, just as Yuba had said, they held a small welcome party together.

Chapter 4: Parting

The next morning, the village women witnessed an odd sight at the daily food trade.

Gon and his followers were tied up in the pillory as criminals in the village square. Hayate’s subordinates stood next to them as guards, watching over them as they explained the reason why Gon’s group was being restrained.

In a little under an hour, the events that had happened the previous night had spread throughout the village.

The story being told went something like this: Gon’s group had tried to go night crawling and attacked Ruri and Sayo. However, Rio immediately noticed their intrusion and paid them back with a fight. As a result, Rio had thoroughly beaten up the ringleader, Gon. Rio left him out in the bone-chilling cold autumn air all night in only his underwear as a punishment.

The villagers had been filled with rage when they heard about the night crawling, but once they saw Gon’s horribly swollen face and shivering body, their anger was quelled by his well-deserved treatment.

And so, last night’s incident became the talk of the village from early morning onward. When Rio went out that morning to trade for ingredients, the villagers praised his achievement with welcoming smiles.

Rio had already reflected on his actions last night and felt rather uncomfortable with their praise, but he did his best to not let that show on the outside, and went about his day as usual. The same went for when he was around Yuba, Ruri, Sayo, and Hayate.

Hayate’s closest aides and subordinates had all gone out on business supervising and interrogating Gon’s gang, leaving only Yuba, Ruri, Rio, Sayo, and Hayate left in the village chief’s house.

Yuba and Hayate were awake already, but Ruri and Sayo hadn’t fallen asleep until very late, so Rio offered to be the one to prepare breakfast, which was why he was out trading ingredients in the morning. Once breakfast was ready and the girls had woken up, everyone gathered in the living room.

“Everyone... I’m sorry for the trouble I caused yesterday. Please accept my deepest apologies,” Rio said to everyone once more.

Last night, Rio had displayed what was truly violent behavior in front of Ruri and Sayo, who were just simple village girls — it wouldn’t have been odd if his carelessness had hurt them enough to cause some kind of trauma. Subjecting others to the sight of his fury also served as a form of violence, after all. That was why Rio wanted to apologize properly and take responsibility for his mistake; he would accept all blame without making excuses.

“There’s nothing for you to apologize for. Thank you for protecting Ruri and Sayo.” Yuba shook her head on behalf of everyone, smiling gently at Rio to ease his worries.

Rio was slightly taken aback for a moment, before he frowned. “But, Ruri and Sayo were frightened because of me...”

“You don’t need to worry about Ruri and Sayo. Isn’t that right, you two?” Yuba said, looking at the girls.

“Yup. To be honest, I was a little scared... But then Sayo said Rio was so angry because he wanted to save us so much. We shouldn’t be scared by that. Otherwise, it’d hurt Rio,” Ruri said with an apologetic look and nodded.

“It’s not Sir Rio’s fault! So please, don’t apologize.” Sayo appealed to Rio in earnest, nodding her head furiously.

“Lord Rio, it is exactly as they say. I may be overstepping my boundaries as an outsider, but you do not need to let this bother you. If you had not hit him, I would have done so instead,” Hayate agreed with a shrug.

“...Thank you very much, everyone. But, it is true that my rage blinded me from properly considering my actions... There were better methods I could have used to save you. So please, allow me to apologize.”

Unable to bear his emotions, Rio’s face nearly twisted into a grimace. He grit his teeth and bowed his head instead. Everyone’s warm words seeped into his body, but it wasn’t that easy for him to change his attitude just because the people involved offered their words of forgiveness so easily.

“What an honest boy. Just like a certain someone else,” Yuba said with a huff of laughter.

“A certain someone?” Ruri asked Yuba with a curious look.

“Hmm... More importantly, Rio woke up early to make us this breakfast. We should eat up before it cools. There are still many issues left to deal with, too — I have to summon their village chief here to discuss what to do with those boys, so let’s wrap things up quickly,” Yuba said cheerfully, changing the topic.

Hayate’s attendants were currently assisting them by traveling out to Gon’s village, tasked with bringing the village chief and relatives of the criminals back with them. They would arrive in a day or two to discuss the incident that had occurred.

Everyone gave a strained smile and dug into their food in agreement.

“Sayo! Is Sayo all right?! What about Ruri?!” The front door slammed open, revealing Shin and the other youths.

“B-Brother?!” Their sudden appearance made Sayo widen her eyes in shock.

“Oh my, everyone at once?” Ruri laughed bitterly.

“O-Ooh! Sayo, Ruri! Are you two all right?!” Shin asked in a flurry once he spotted Sayo and Ruri.

“We’re fine, and you’re being noisy. Aren’t you a bit late to come running now?” Yuba said in a tired voice.

“W-We were drinking at the boss’ house until late last night, so we k-kinda... slept in. Then Ume came barging in and told us everything. I-I’m... I’m sorry,” Shin and the others panted as they apologized, their expressions guilty.

“I figured that was the case. Well, rest assured: the incident was a failed attempt. Rio beat Gon to a pulp, and his co-conspirators were apprehended by Lord Hayate. Did you not see them hanging their heads in the square?” Yuba said with an exasperated smile.

“N-No, we ran here as fast as we could...”

“Well, that’s how it is. I can fill you in on the details later, so why don’t you go and give Gon a piece of your mind before you head home? The girls are fine, as you can see.”

“O-Okay...” The boys nodded, retreating dejectedly. Shin, however, remained.

“Mr. Hayate, and... Rio, too. Th... Thank you for saving these two!” he said with gratitude, shooting Rio a somewhat embarrassed glance as he did so. The youths exchanged looks with each other before they all turned back to murmur words of gratitude.

“I did not do anything special — all of the glory should go to Lord Rio.” Hayate shook his head with a quiet laugh. Rio gave a somewhat uncomfortable smile as Ruri and Sayo giggled.

“See you later, then,” Shin said shyly, turning on his heel; the other young men followed him out. Yuba snorted in amusement as she watched their retreating backs.

Later on, when the boys saw the miserable state that Gon and the others in the square were in, they vowed to themselves to never pick a fight with Rio again.

◇◇◇

Two days later, the village chief of Gon’s group arrived, led by Hayate’s aides. The party was summoned to the village hall to meet with Yuba; Rio was also sitting in on the meeting alongside Hayate, who was acting as a witness.

“How does your village intend on compensating for this incident?” Yuba asked the village chief — Gon’s father — who sat directly opposite of her.

“We have also been at our wit’s end with these youths in our village. While this particular incident was most inexcusable, I would like to consider it an unlucky accident,” Gon’s father answered vaguely, shaking his head from side to side in an exaggerated way.

“Does that mean you shall bear responsibility for the chaos that Gon has caused? Those boys are primarily your responsibility, correct?”

“That is a separate matter. Our village will not object to whatever form of punishment you choose, but their actions are their own responsibility. They are adults, after all.” Yuba’s pursuit to deem him the responsible party made Gon’s father resort to making excuses.

There were no objections from those behind him, either. They seemed to have accepted giving up on the criminals during their journey here.

“I know your village is struggling to maintain your livelihood as is. I can understand why you would not want to take on anymore unnecessary burdens... However, we have no intentions of backing down without a fight. For now, allow me to inform you of what we aim to do,” Yuba said, before presenting her suggestions on how to deal with the incident.

“First — and this is the only point in which we will not concede — Gon will be handed over to the kingdom for punishment. From what Lord Hayate has told us, he will most likely end up in penal slavery.”

“Indeed, that is justified.” Gon’s father nodded in annoyance. Though his response seemed cruel, Gon’s existence had become that much of a burden to him.

“Next, with regard to the other men who were complicit in assisting Gon... Even if we handed them over to the kingdom, they probably wouldn’t be sentenced to penal slavery. They would either be whipped a few times, or given a short jail sentence, before being released. To be honest, that is not enough to quell our resentment; we wish to receive due compensation. Which brings me to this: we will take a few of the worst in the group and sell them in the capital as contracted slaves, then receive the money from that as compensation,” Yuba explained in a collected manner.

“...While it is true that contracted slaves can fetch a fair amount, I doubt the men will agree. What are the terms of your intended slave contract?” Gon’s father asked doubtfully.

There was one crucial condition to forming a slave contract with someone: the agreement of the one being contracted as the slave. In order to forcibly form a slave contract without the consent of the person in question, either bankruptcy or a debt bond, along with witnesses, were required.

In regards to this situation, Gon’s gang wasn’t burdened with any debt, nor did they have bonds with which to pay any compensation money. No matter how much guilt they had in complying with the crime, it was hard to imagine they would follow through with the procedure of becoming slaves.

“That is where we would like to ask for your cooperation. If you work together with us, then we can promise not to pursue your village for any further responsibility. How does that sound?” Yuba grinned, her eyes fixed on Gon’s father.

“...What am I cooperating with?” Gon’s father cautiously asked in return.

“We want you to tell the boys that you were able to negotiate for everyone, other than Gon, to be pardoned from being handed over to the kingdom... under the condition of paying a compensation fee.”

“...They do not have the savings to pay for such a fee. Even if they return to our village, they will simply be ostracized,” Gon’s father interjected sarcastically.

“Yes, but do listen until the end. I know that they do not have any savings. That is why you are going to tell them that you shouldered the fee for them, then use that as reason to issue a debt bond. Once there is a bond, we can use that as the reason to attach a slavery contract on the group of them. The rest you understand, right?”

“Wha—?!” Gon’s father widened his eyes in shock, expression stiffening. “I-Isn’t that rather underhanded? It’s true that they may agree to slavery that way, but it seems as though we are deceiving them... To go that far is...” he said with a hint of guilty conscience.

The parents of the co-conspirators behind him stirred noisily.

“Hm. I know that night crawling is customary in a village society, but it is only allowed with the consent of both parties. Attempting rape on the other party is a crime on par with robbery and murder, and the accomplices that assisted Gon have to pay their dues. Your children’s stupidity has given my precious granddaughter emotional trauma she’ll have to carry for her entire life. I have no intention of giving in easily.”

“H-Hmm...” Yuba’s furious declaration left Gon’s father at a loss for words.

“If you refuse to cooperate, then I don’t have any other options. We’ll simply return to the beginning of our discussion, and have your village take primary responsibility instead. Oh, and for the time being, we’ve confiscated the trade items that were loaded onto your cargo carriage,” Yuba informed Gon’s father nonchalantly upon seeing his half-hearted response.

“...H-Hah? W-What did you just say?”

“I said, we are holding the trade items that were loaded onto your cargo carriage as collateral for our compensation fee.”

“Y-You must be kidding me! Those items belong to our village... This is tyranny — a robbery! ...Lord Hayate, surely such behavior cannot be tolerated?!” Gon’s father yelled in a panic and pleaded with Hayate, who had been standing to the side and listening.

“...I am sorry, but your village was the one that allowed such wild people to act as your representatives in the trade squad. A great part of the responsibility falls onto you. You may have intended on tactfully banishing them if they caused any issues, but the kingdom is not about to act just because Lady Yuba has confiscated your village’s trade goods,” Hayate said, shaking his head coldly.

“T-That can’t be...” Gon’s father slumped over in despair. The profits gained by selling their trade items were vital in supporting the villagers’ livelihood; without them, the village would suffer greatly.

“That is why I am giving you a choice. You were the ones who raised your children in such a way, no? Either you make those boys take responsibility for their own actions, or you can wipe their asses for them. It is up to you.” Yuba pressed them for a decision mercilessly.

“...All right. We’ll have them take responsibility.” Gon’s father hung his head and agreed after a moment’s hesitation.

◇◇◇

After the discussions regarding Gon’s gang had wrapped up, Rio visited the northern hill where his parents’ graves were, all by himself. The sun was beginning to dip down, and the fall scenery before him was stained a madder red. Rio stood before his parents’ graves and gently touched his right hand to the stone pillar.

He reflected on the moment he nearly beat Gon to death. For the three days since the incident, Rio had constantly been looking into his own heart.

At that moment in time, I truly had the intent to kill in me. That intent turned to violence... I was going to kill Gon; I didn’t care about killing another human...

Rio removed his hand from the pillar and stared at both of his palms. It was an emotion that Rio was familiar with... No, he wasn’t simply familiar with it; he had once felt that emotion toward one person in particular.

Malice powerful enough to make him feel nauseous.

Overflowing hatred strong enough to make him go mad.

A pure, pitch-black killing intent... All toward the man who took his mother from him.

Yes, Rio once tried to exact revenge against that man. It was all he thought about, all he wished for as he lived in the hellish environment of the slums.

But... When did that all change?

When did he begin to think of murder as the most primitive wrongdoing humans could commit?

When did he realize that vengeance was not a forgivable motive for murder?

When was he able to shut out the sinister emotions that slept within?

The answer was obvious. It was since the very moment Rio began to harbor the memories of Amakawa Haruto inside of him.

The human named Amakawa Haruto had averted his eyes.

Rio himself hated the man who had murdered his mother, but Amakawa Haruto within him had his hesitations about revenge.

Nothing would come from vengeance, and his mother wouldn’t want him to resort to it. Even if he got his revenge, nothing would be left for him.

Besides, since he had come to hate that way of life, he understood that acts such as taking revenge, killing people, and defiling his hands would make him the same as that man, no matter how much he justified it to himself.

He didn’t want to know or realize that feeling.

He was an egoist — a dirty human just like that man. An arrogant, ugly human, living only as he desired. It was easier to live that way, to lick his wounds and cover up the truth with empty words.

That was why Rio had hesitated to kill anyone, because he believed it was wrong to do so. By restraining himself, he had thought he could become an honest person who didn’t cause any inconveniences for others.

It would have been a wonderful thing, but they were all hollow words. Nothing more than ideals... Ones that didn’t comply with the cruel reality of this world.

Humans were not the same. There were all kinds of people in the world — some were rational, some were self-centered, and each had their own set of morals. That was why humans clashed with each other; when they did, their true character was revealed.

For instance, it would be ideal if a compromise could be reached during those clashes, but that wasn’t always the case. Some humans took advantage of others under the name of compromise in order to pursue their own gains. Some would even purposefully clash with others out of ill will.

Rio had also met and clashed with all kinds of people throughout his life; even so, there hadn’t been anyone Rio could bare his true character toward, until Gon had forcibly exposed Rio’s true character.

He could not turn into a human like the man who killed his mother.

With that thought, Rio had fought to become a rational and honest person... Until he followed his instincts and tried to kill Gon, to dirty his hands. The incident was enough to make him aware of his hypocrisy and naivety.

That was why Rio understood that he wanted to continue being a rational person with strong self-control, an honest person who didn’t inconvenience others. And yet, regardless of his intent and regardless of morals, there were some people he couldn’t forgive by any means.

This was the second time I wanted to kill someone. No... I actually tried to kill him. With these hands, and all of my own will, I tried to kill Gon. Because of that...

Now that he understood, he couldn’t remain his naive self any longer. In this world, those at the top could rest on their laurels, toy with the weak, and gloat in self-satisfaction. Those kinds of people could make a move on Rio and the people precious to Rio at any time.

Sometimes, they would force cruel decisions to be made, which was why it was necessary to prepare oneself for the worst.

I can’t run. And I can’t turn back... So I should start moving forward already. This is a departure from the weakest part of me.

He wouldn’t run anymore. He didn’t want to run anymore. He had to accept the negative side of himself... In order to live. In order to protect others. He wouldn’t begrudge himself for dirtying his hands.

Rio bit down on his lip and swore this to himself, then sneered at himself in a bitter but invigorated way.

I guess I’ll head back to Strahl after a little while longer, he thought to himself.

On this day, Rio changed his former helplessness and bitterness into determination.

Chapter 5: To the Capital

Two days after Gon’s punishment was decided, the time had finally come for the trade squad of Yuba’s village to depart for the capital.

Despite the early hour of the morning, huge crowds of people had gathered in the village square, where several horse-drawn carriages were standing by. Among them was not only the trade squad, but Hayate’s party as well.

Hayate’s party was heading to the next neighboring village in the direction of the capital, so it was decided that they would accompany the trade squad part of the way. Furthermore, several of Hayate’s attendants would be staying with the trade squad in order to escort the members of Gon’s gang that would become slaves to the capital.

“Hurry! Make sure that none of the annual tax has been left unloaded! The carriage with the prisoners will bring up the rear. And to those escorting: be sure to not take your eyes off of them for even a moment,” Hayate commanded his aides briskly from his horse.

A dozen or so people were running around in a flurry.

“Lord Hayate.” Ruri addressed him from the ground beside his horse.

“Hm? O-Oh. Lady Ruri, how may I assist you?”

“Oh, no. I just wanted to express my gratitude for all that you’ve done to accommodate us, Lord Hayate. You didn’t have to dismount from your horse.”

Hayate had gotten off his horse in a hurry, which made Ruri laugh in amusement.

“A-Ah, no, well... It is fine. I did not do anything deserving of such gratitude — I simply fulfilled my duties as an official of this kingdom. If anything, you should be thanking Lord Rio. He was the one who noticed their intrusion on that night, after all.”

“Yes, I’ll definitely offer Rio my gratitude again later, but I won’t be seeing you again for some time. I couldn’t prepare anything fancy, but if you could accept this...” Ruri stuck out her hand bashfully. It was something packed in a small bag.

“...What’s this?” Hayate cocked his head curiously as he accepted it.

“It’s an amulet for good health and warding off evil. I made it in a rush, so it’s a little frayed...” Ruri said bashfully.

“O-Ooh! I am most indebted! I will treasure it greatly.” Overcome with emotion, Hayate expressed his deepest gratitude.

“Ahaha, I’m glad you like it.”

“Of course. It is the greatest gift one could hope to receive. I wish I could gift you something too, but I am most regrettably not in possession of such an item at this moment. I will bring one with me next time I visit.”

“This is a gift to thank you for taking care of me, so I can’t possibly accept anything else from you. Ah, but please, feel free to visit any time you like. An amulet is barely enough to make up for all you’ve done, but we’ll always welcome you in our boring little village.”

“O-Of course. Then, perhaps on my next vacation...” At Ruri’s strained smile, Hayate hesitantly nodded his head.

“We’ll be waiting for you. Ah, also, Granny wanted to give you something too—” Ruri suddenly remembered. She looked around for Yuba.

“I’m right here. Lord Hayate, there’s a small favor I’d like to ask of you, if you’d care to lend an ear?” Yuba approached as though she had been awaiting her chance.

“Certainly. I will assist you to the best of my ability.” Hayate nodded readily.

“Ruri, you go see Rio and Sayo off,” Yuba said, creating an opportunity for Hayate and herself to be alone.

“Please hand this letter to your father, Lord Gouki,” Yuba said, handing Hayate a rolled-up parchment with emphasis.

“To my father?”

“Yes. It is a very important letter, so I would appreciate it if you handed it over to him in person.”

“I see. Consider it done — I promise you I will deliver it with these very hands.” Hayate accepted the letter with a fierce nod and carefully tucked it away in his clothes.

“I am most grateful.”

“It is of no inconvenience to me, as I would have seen my father once I returned home anyway. For you to be using valuable paper for this, I can assume it must be of a serious matter. Please, leave it to me.”

“Indeed. Then please allow me to repay you at a later date. Let’s see... How about when Lord Hayate comes to visit Ruri?” Yuba said, the corners of her mouth turning up in a small grin.

“D-Did you hear what Ruri and I were saying earlier, by any chance? I-It is not that I am coming to see only Ruri, but I will look forward to it nevertheless,” Hayate said at an oddly rapid pace, sounding almost as though he was giving some kind of an excuse.

“Is that so? Well, that girl is already of age, and I would be more concerned if she remained an old spinster forever. It would be most fortunate if you could visit sooner rather than later.”

“A-As I said, Lady Ruri and I are not...”

Seeing Hayate’s faltering made Yuba huff with laughter and put on a smile. “Yes, so please come visit before she finds another to take her hand in marriage. It wouldn’t be good to come all the way here just to visit a married woman, after all.”

“Uh... That... is a good point.” Hayate widened his eyes and nodded with a strained smile. For some reason, he felt like he was just baited.

Meanwhile, a short distance away from Yuba and Hayate, Rio was talking to the two girls.

“Wow. It feels like so long since I’ve seen you in that outfit, Rio. You wore it when you arrived in the village... and a couple of times during your training, I think?” Ruri commented in amazement at the sight of Rio fully decked out in his gear.

Rio had equipped the complete set of dwarven-made armor he received from the spirit folk village. He wore his black overcoat on top of everything else. During his stay in the village, he had rarely ever fully equipped himself, so it was just as Ruri had said.

“Come to think of it, it’s been over half a year since Sir Rio came to this village...” Sayo folded her fingers over as she counted off the months Rio had been with them.

“Time sure flies. Rio’s one of us villagers now.” Ruri nodded wholeheartedly, then bowed her head. “Rio, please protect Sayo and all of the villagers on your journey. Please,” she said with a serious expression.

“Yes, leave it to me.” Rio nodded his head with a faint smile.

“Thank you. And... I’m sorry.” Ruri said with a somewhat regretful face.

“For what?” Rio tilted his head, unsure of what she was apologizing for.

“I reflected on... what happened a few days ago. The more I thought about everything with a calm disposition, the more I realized I did something terrible to Rio. I thanked you, but I didn’t apologize. That’s why I wanted to say sorry before you left for the capital. I figured it’d be too late if I waited until you came back...”

Ruri explained her reason for apologizing with an expression that conveyed how unbearable she found her own emotions, when Sayo hurriedly cut in.

“U-Umm! In that case, I’d like to apologize to Sir Rio too!”

“No, Sayo. You tried to take action for Rio’s sake before you even thought of yourself. I wasn’t like that.” Ruri shook her head.

“T-That’s not tru—”

“Please wait a minute, you two,” Rio interrupted, sensing that the conversation was about to devolve into bickering. Ruri and Sayo both looked at Rio in unison.

“The root of the problem was my lack of consideration. I was so infuriated; I couldn’t see my surroundings and ended up scaring the two of you. That’s why I should be the one to apologize,” Rio said with a guilty expression.

“That’s not true!”

“That is not true at all!”

Ruri and Sayo’s strong objections overlapped with each other, as though they had planned it in advance.

Rio’s eyes widened in shock for a moment, before he let out an amused laugh. “...Haha.”

“W-What’s so funny?” Ruri and Sayo exchanged glances bashfully.

“How about a handshake?” Rio said, suddenly offering his right hand out to the girls.

“Huh? A handshake?”

“A handshake of reconciliation. We all have things we refuse to concede to, but I would like to meet you two halfway in spite of that. So, let’s shake on it. That way, with this, everything will return to normal,” Rio said, leaving Ruri and Sayo both blinking blankly.

“Y-Yeah. Thanks, and sorry. I’m sorry, Rio...” Ruri came to her senses with a gasp and shook Rio’s hand.

“Sayo, too. May we shake hands?” After his handshake with Ruri, Rio turned to address Sayo, who was still standing there in a daze.

“Huh?! ...Ah, y-yes! I-If that’s all right with you!”

Sayo wiped her hand against her clothes and offered her right hand to Rio in a panic. Rio gave a faint grin and shook her hand, making Sayo immediately freeze with a flush, while Ruri watched the two of them with a pleasant smile on her face.

“...Take these, you two. They’re amulets for good health and warding off evil.”

After Rio let go of Sayo’s hand, Ruri offered them the same amulet she had given Hayate.

“Thank you very much. I’ll treasure it.”

“T-Thank you, Ruri!”

Rio and Sayo gratefully accepted the amulets.

“Yup. Let’s hang out together again when you get back.” Ruri suggested.

“Yes, please,” Rio immediately agreed with a smile.

“Okay, have a good trip. Sayo, make sure you stay by Rio’s side. He’ll protect you no matter what.”

“Huh? O-Okay...” Sayo ducked her head in embarrassment.

“All right! It looks like Lord Hayate’s party is ready. Time to head out!” The leader of the trade squad, Dola, yelled out.

“Right, we’ll be off then. Let’s go, Sayo.”

“Y-Yes!” Rio began walking, Sayo on his heels.

After the other villagers had said their farewells, Rio and Sayo climbed into the horse-drawn carriage headed for the capital. Yuba, Ruri, and the other villagers all saw them off as the carriages finally departed from the village, proceeding down the road toward the capital with a clattering noise.

There was a risk of being attacked by bandits or wild animals while on the road, but the dozen or so villagers were all relatively geared for the occasion. Thankfully, their journey was uneventful, and they pulled up to the next village a little past noon.

Hayate’s party would be splitting off here, but several members of his squad would be remaining with the villagers in order to escort the criminals to the capital.

“Lord Hayate, thank you for everything you’ve done,” Rio called out and bowed. He descended from the horse-drawn carriage he had been riding on to give his parting words to Hayate.

Hayate dismounted from the horse in one smooth movement before brightly responding to Rio.

“No, I have been in your debt as well, Lord Rio. Let us sit down and have a chat again when we have the opportunity. I would also like to spar with you once, if possible. If you ever visit the capital on another occasion, feel free to drop by my home. I would be glad to assist you if need be.”

“Thank you very much. I plan on leaving the village eventually, but I will make sure to stop by before I leave the kingdom.”

“I see... Is that so. I am a bit saddened to hear that, but fate will decide if we are destined to meet again. If anything happens on your way to the capital, please rely on my attendants. Be well.”

“Yes. You take care of yourself, too, Lord Hayate.”

Rio and Hayate exchanged lighthearted words and a firm handshake, then nodded at each other before they parted ways.

After that, the road to the capital continued to be peaceful, and the party proceeded down the road as a fall breeze blew around them.

Several days later, Rio and the others arrived at the capital.

◇◇◇

Rio had arrived at the capital of the Karasuki Kingdom.

An enormous structure towered in the middle of the capital, its architecture resembling a Japanese-style castle. Equally large castle walls ran along its perimeter. As one would expect from the capital, the town that surrounded the castle was vast and spread out, bearing a population of tens of thousands of people.

With barely any opportunity to visit the capital, most villagers would get lost immediately. However, Rio’s party were directly led by Dola and Hayate’s aides to their destination: the lodging they would use for the duration of their stay. It went without saying that Hayate’s aides knew where to go, and Dola had apparently visited the capital numerous times before.

Their lodging was a shared accommodation facility managed by the kingdom that could house several dozen guests at once. Traveling merchants and villagers selling their own products, much like Rio’s party, were able to use the lodgings without interruption, so there was a fair demand for them. And because they were renting the space, they had to do all the cooking and laundry themselves during their stay.

Eventually, the party secured a lodging and stopped their carriages.

“All right. We’ll be living here during our stay, so make sure you remember the location, and don’t get lost out there. Make sure you’re accompanied by someone who’s been to the capital before when you go out,” Dola said in a joking manner. Main roads aside, the smaller paths really were like a maze, so his words weren’t completely dismissible as a joke. The younger villagers laughed as they nodded, but the elder ones nudged them. “It’s no laughing matter,” they said.

Dola smiled wryly when he noticed that interaction.

“Okay. Now, I’m going to go out for a bit, so I’ll leave the unpacking of the cargo to you guys. Rio, could you come with me? And... Shin, you too.”

“Yes, sure.” Summoned by Dola, Rio and Shin made their way after him.

After they had walked for a while, Dola explained the reason he had called them out. “We’re going to have Lord Hayate’s subordinates accompany us to take Gon’s group to the internment camp. It’s possible they may require some kind of witness statement, but I’d prefer not to take Sayo, if possible. Sorry Rio, but I’d like you to come along. And you too, Shin, as Sayo’s brother. Is that all right?”

“If that’s all it is, then I don’t mind at all. Please let me see things through until the end.” Rio’s expression tensed as he gave a firm nod.

“Well, I have to see the final moments of the rotten bastard that attacked Sayo,” Shin also agreed with a hateful expression.

Thus, the three of them met up with Hayate’s attendants, who had been waiting a short distance away. Next to them was the carriage with Gon and the others.

“Right. Sorry to keep you waiting,” Dola said to Hayate’s aides.

“No, we don’t mind — this is our job. However, the internment camp is a fair distance away from here. We’d like to depart immediately so that we can arrive before sundown.”

Under the guidance of Hayate’s aides, the party headed toward the internment camp. With their objective being what it was, the atmosphere was rather gloomy and quiet.

After walking for about thirty minutes, they finally arrived at their destination.

Located near the center of the capital was an area where the kingdom’s civil service office buildings were clustered. Once they stopped in front of one particularly large and sturdy-looking building, a security guard approached them. He asked about their business, to which Hayate’s attendant explained their situation. Thanks to that, the process went along smoothly and several officials and guards were called out of the building to release Gon and the others from the carriage.

“Get out!”

Once the door was open, a guard barked out an order to Gon and the others within. Knowing they would be cut down immediately if they tried to flee here, Gon’s group obediently appeared from within the carriage. Their hands were bound, restricting their movement greatly.

“...Eek!” The moment Gon spotted Rio among the crowd of people, he instinctively tried to back away in fright. However, a nearby guard used the pole of his spear to smack him on the head.

“No moving around!”

“Gah!”

The impact was strong enough for Gon to lose balance and topple over. He was restrained where he lay face down, the chained collar snapping shut around his neck.

“F-Fuck. Fuck this...” Gon’s voice was pathetic as his body shook.

Beside him, the men who had assisted Gon were unanimously denying their involvement and claiming they were deceived as the guards indifferently snapped collars around their necks, one after another.

Rio watched on, emotionless.

“Take them away — we will now conduct the necessary procedures. Follow us, please,” an official said to Rio and the others before heading inside.

The guards pulled the chains that were attached to the prisoners’ necks and entered the building with familiar strides.

“We should go, too.”

Dola gave a tired sigh and headed inside the building. Rio also took in a breath before walking forward, and Shin brought up the rear with rather nervous steps.

A surprisingly neat and tidy space welcomed them once they entered the building, with what looked like a reception desk directly opposite the door. Several merchant-like people were waiting in line.

“This place takes in not only criminal slaves, but regular slaves too. That’s why merchants come and go in order to purchase stock,” Dola explained to Shin, who was curiously looking around the room.

After that, Rio and the others were led to a waiting room, where they were told to stand by during the procedures. They waited for several minutes before the door of the waiting room opened.

“Sorry for the wait. But, thanks to the testimony that Lord Hayate provided, the judgment came much quicker than expected. The decision was settled — Gon will be a penal slave, while the others will be contract slaves for their debts,” Hayate’s subordinate said as he entered. He gave his report with a wry smile, feeling relaxed after the procedure had gone smoother than expected.

“Ooh, I’m glad to hear that. Why does it normally take longer?” Dola asked with wide eyes.

“Well, you see... Normally, even a criminal caught red-handed would undergo an informal trial to receive judgment, but the case was closed this time with just a document examination.”

“I see. In that case, please give Lord Hayate our deepest thanks when you see him again.”

“Of course — I shall let him know. Also, here is the victim compensation paid out from Gon being taken into custody as a penal slave. It contains one gold coin,” Hayate’s aide said, holding out a small bag with the compensation money. A single gold coin was enough for an average household in the capital to live off for several months.

“Oh, wow... So much?” Dola’s eyes widened in shock.

“Well, he was an awfully burly man. His bounty was valued at the highest level.” Hayate’s subordinate shrugged with a wry smile.

“I see...”

“For the remaining contract slaves, you can either have them assessed and bought out immediately by the government office, or put them up for auction. Auctions do take both time and effort, but you could potentially get a much higher price than the instant buyout depending on the qualities of the slaves. Which will you go with?”

“In that case, please go with the buyout,” Dola chose without a moment’s hesitation.

“All right. Then, I shall inform them immediately. Please wait a bit longer until the assessments are done.” The aide nodded, then turned on his heel and left the room once again.

“Boss, is that really okay? Wouldn’t we be able to get more if we put them on auction?” Shin asked Dola.

“It’s fine. This method will cause less trouble in the future, and I don’t wanna see their faces anymore.” Dola replied frankly and shook his head.

“...Fine. It kinda feels anticlimactic, though.” Everything had proceeded so smoothly that Shin didn’t seem quite satisfied.

“Well, this is what it’s like when someone loses their humanity like that. You may not be used to it, but I’ll take you out for a good meal later so you can forget all of this and start anew,” Dola said to clear the strangely depressing atmosphere, ruffling Shin’s head roughly.

“S-Stop that, boss! Not in front of him!”

Shin glanced at Rio and resisted Dola in embarrassment, feeling overly aware of the fact that he was being treated like a child. Rio chuckled with a smile as he watched the two of them in amusement.

◇◇◇

By the time Rio and the others had collected their buyout money and left the internment center, the sun was already setting in the sky; most of the day had already passed them by.

“Since we’ve received the compensation money and all, let’s start heading back. I’ll buy you two some of the famous local kamutan!” Dola said on their way back to their lodgings.

“Ooh! Yeah!” Shin cheered happily.

“What’s... kamutan?” Rio asked, having never heard the word before.

“Oh, what? You’ve never had kamutan before?” Shin looked at Rio with a somewhat pleased expression.

“I haven’t. What kind of food is it?”

“I see. Well, how should I put it? It’s a steamy hot bowl of soup with long and thin noodles made of rice flour and wheat flower. You slurp it up, and it tastes great.”

At Rio’s earnest question, Shin gave a simple explanation of kamutan with a smug expression. He moved his hands, making the gesture of slurping noodles.

“...Hmm, that certainly seems good.” Rio could imagine what kind of food kamutan was by Shin’s explanation.

Noodles, huh? Ramen, soba, udon... No, it uses rice flour as well as wheat flour, so maybe it’s something like pho on Earth?

At any rate, his interest was piqued. Rio loved cooking and food in general more than anything, so he was immediately filled with the desire to try it as soon as possible.

“It doesn’t just seem good, it is good. You’ll see once you eat it.”

“You were really touched when you ate it for the first time, too. You even tried to get Sayo to make it for you after you got back to the village... She hadn’t tried it before, so you two ended up fighting, if I recall correctly,” Dola teased Shin boastfully.

Shin recoiled in embarrassment, then flared up at Rio, who watched him in amusement. However, it wasn’t with a hostile attitude: Shin, who had previously avoided having conversations with Rio, was now able to hold proper conversations with him, despite being a tad bit blunt at times.

Perhaps he had a slight change of heart after Rio saved Sayo during the Gon incident.

The three of them chatted energetically as they made their way back to their lodgings. After handing the compensation money they received from the government office to the men waiting at their accommodations, they left once again to get a bite to eat. Since it was their first day in the capital and the fatigue of their journey lingered on, they decided to split into small groups and take turns getting food.

Thus, Rio, Shin, and Dola went out to eat kamutan as planned. They entered Dola’s recommended store, which was a ten minute walk away from their shared accommodation.

“Hey, please get us three large servings of kamutan. With extra meat, too,” Dola ordered with familiarity. A strong “You got it!” could be heard in response from the kitchen.

Minutes later, the rumored kamutan was done.

“Here ya go — three large servings of kamutan with extra meat! Thanks for waiting!” A waiter brought the bowls of kamutan over to Rio’s table cheerfully.

Rio had been asking the other two for more details about kamutan as they waited, but once he saw the real thing, he found it extremely similar to ramen.

However, as it was a food that had been eaten in the Kingdom of Karasuki since ancient times, it probably wasn’t the invention of a reincarnated person, as Liselotte had introduced pasta to the Strahl region, for example.

“It’s tradition to eat kamutan with hearty slurps,” Shin said proudly as he began to eat the noodles.

Rio dug into the steaming-hot kamutan with his chopsticks. First, he took a mouthful of soup; the flavor tasted similar to a light shoyu ramen soup. Next, he scooped up the noodles with practiced movements, and brought them to his mouth.

The noodles had a unique texture from the rice flour, but it was springy and elastic. The meat wasn’t chashu, but it was seasoned appropriately and suited the noodles and soup well.

...It’s good.

It had been a long time since he had eaten something similar to ramen. In actuality, if the noodles had been made from wheat, the soup altered a little, and with chashu, the kamutan would have been exactly the same as ramen.

I should try making ramen someday, Rio thought, his mouth turning up into a happy smile.

◇◇◇

The next day, before noon...

Beneath the dazzling blue sky of the capital, Rio walked through the shopping district of the castle town with Sayo, having been requested to buy luxury items by the rest of the trade squad.

As for the others in the trade squad: some had gone out to sell their village’s products, some were out buying large amounts of necessities, while others stayed behind to watch over their accommodations.

“There really are a lot of people in the capital,” Sayo said curiously as she watched the road.

“Is this your first time in the capital?” Rio asked from where he was walking beside her.

“Yes. My brother has visited before, but I’ve always stayed at home. He would always tell me all sorts of stories, so I really wanted to see it for myself!”

“I heard about it. Shin pestered you to make kamutan and you two ended up fighting, or something?”

“Yeah. He just kept bragging about how he went to the capital, so I got a little fed up. I can’t make food I’ve never eaten before, so I got mad,” Sayo said with a shy grin.

“Did you end up making it?”

“It didn’t work out. It came out kinda slimy and sticky...”

“Soup aside, you need more than just rice flour and wheat flour to make the noodles. If you don’t have the knowledge, it’d be impossible to make.”

“Huh? Do you know how to make it, Sir Rio?”

“Yes. While it wasn’t kamutan, I have made other noodles before.”

“U-Umm... Could you teach me sometime, then?” Sayo asked cautiously.

“Sure, I wouldn’t mind. Let’s try making it together when we return to the village,” Rio replied with a nod.

“Thank you very much! I actually haven’t eaten it yet...”

“Then, how about we go eat it together after this? Since we’re in the capital and all,” Rio offered as a suggestion after Sayo had happily thanked him.

“Yes! I’d love to!” Sayo nodded enthusiastically.

“Let’s keep an eye out for a restaurant while we’re buying the items everyone requested.”

With that, the two of them decided to go eat kamutan for lunch. Yet...

The store Dola took us to is far from here, so I don’t know which store to go to... Rio thought without letting it show on his face. He wanted to take a chance so that Sayo could eat delicious food, but unfortunately, he had no experience visiting the Kingdom of Karasuki.

Perhaps this group matchup wasn’t the best one for going shopping together... We don’t even know where to find restaurants. It’s Sayo’s first time in the capital, too. We don’t have any idea of what’s around...

He had asked the members of the trade squad their reasoning behind grouping them this way before they left to go shopping, but they had forced it upon him for some unknown reason. Sure enough, the two of them had to walk around all morning in search of the items, comparing market prices and stock quality.

It was more like they were sightseeing than shopping; fortunately, Sayo was in a good mood from being with Rio, and didn’t seem particularly dissatisfied. She was innocently enjoying her time shopping.

Rio had been secretly worried the incident with Gon had left her traumatized, but Sayo showed no indication of such a thing as she willfully insisted on her own participation in the trade squad. It was reassuring.

“Sir Rio, why don’t we just ask a local if there’s a store they recommend?” Sayo said with a carefree smile.

“...You’re right. Let’s ask someone in the next store we go to.” Rio set aside his needless worries and nodded, his smile small.

Well, as long as Sayo is having fun, he reasoned. Thankfully, the amount of luxuries they had to buy wasn’t that much, so the two of them continued walking around the shopping district.

“You two youngins, over there. On a date, are we?” A young woman called out to Rio and Sayo. She seemed to be selling trinkets for women, and she had her stock set out on a mat in front of her.

“Huh? M-Me? Eh, ah, no... Erm...” Sayo tried to respond with something, confused. Sayo realized the merchant woman was talking to her and flushed bright red.

“We came to the capital to sell our village’s products. It’s just a shopping trip,” Rio explained on behalf of the naive Sayo.

It was clear the merchant woman was trying to strike up a conversation for the sake of business. While it normally would have been best to ignore her and keep walking, Sayo had stopped with goodwill in mind, so it was a bit hard to leave now.

“I see. Is that so... Hmm...” The merchant woman nodded vaguely and looked at Sayo, who was still acting embarrassed. Sayo’s cheeks turned scarlet under the woman’s gaze, who seemed to see right through her.

“How about it, mister? A souvenir to remember your stroll through the capital with such a cute lady by your side?” The woman grinned, turning to target Rio instead.

“T-That’s not true! And I’d feel bad! Ah, and we’re not on a date!” Sayo shook her head in a panic.

Rio glanced at the items lined on the mat. For a street stall, the items were arranged neatly and seemed to be of good quality.

“You’re a natural at this, miss. Sayo, is there anything you want?” Rio asked Sayo with a faint, wry smile.

He wanted to give her something as a small token of his gratitude for taking care of him, as well as to apologize for causing trouble during the Gon incident.

“Fweh... I-It’s all right! I couldn’t ask that of you!” Sayo stuck both her hands out in front of her and shook her head furiously. Her overreaction mimicked a small animal, making Rio laugh in amusement.

“There’s no need to hold back. I’ve been in your care, too, so it’s a thank you present.”

“He’s right. If a man offers to buy a woman a present, then it’s only polite to accept it. Go on, now — at least take a look.” At Rio’s offer, the merchant woman laughed and beckoned Sayo closer.

“Eh, ah... Then, just a look...”

Despite her bewilderment, Sayo decided to look at the items on display. She hesitated at first, but found the items were all to her liking, and a sparkle gradually appeared in her eyes.

“Anything interest you?”

“Erm, stuff like this one I think is cute...” At the merchant woman’s question, Sayo pointed to a flower hairpin that was simple, but cute.

“Ooh, you sure have a good eye, miss! That’s a one-of-a-kind.”

“Umm, is it expensive?”

“Hmm, let’s see. How does two silver coins sound?” The merchant woman asked somewhat cautiously.

Sayo had actually chosen one of the more expensive items available on display. In wasn’t impossible for commoners to buy, but the price was enough to be quite a hit to the wallet if purchased without consideration.

“S-Silver coins?! S-Sir Rio, it’s fine! I... I don’t need it after all!”

As soon as Sayo heard the price, she declined the gift in shock. It was a great amount of money to an average village girl like her.

“I don’t mind. If you like it, Sayo, I’ll buy it for you.” Rio showed no sign of concern for the price and expressed his willingness to purchase it.

“...Huh?” Sayo’s eyes widened slightly.

“Ooh. You’ve got it, mister. But, maybe you should learn how to buy things at a market a bit better...” The merchant woman suggested in surprise.

However, Rio shook his head with a gentle smile.

“I don’t back down because of the price when it comes to a gift for a girl. That price is fine.”

“Ahaha, wonderful! Then, I should’ve made it a little more expensive, huh?” The woman laughed heartily.

“Is this the one you want, then, Sayo?” Rio took two silver coins from his wallet and checked with her one last time.

“Eh? Ah, b-but...”

Sayo hesitantly looked between the hairpin and Rio. The hairpin was extremely attractive, and the thought of receiving a present from Rio made her unbearably happy, but the price was high enough to scare her.

“I-I don’t want it after all—” Just as Sayo tried to say that, Rio paid for the hairpin.

“Okay, miss. Give me that one, please.”

It was clear from Sayo’s reaction that she had taken a liking to this hairpin, so he went ahead and bought it anyway. Knowing Sayo’s personality, he figured she would’ve rejected him if he hadn’t done it this way.

Sayo watched Rio hand over the money with a dazed expression.

“Thanks for the purchase! Would you like a box to protect it, or do you want to put it on right away?” The merchant picked up the hairpin and a box. She stood up and approached Sayo.

“Eh, ah, umm... Y-Yes please!”

“Here, I’ll put it on for you. Stay still for a moment.” Sayo nodded timidly as the merchant woman put the hairpin in her hair. She froze in a dream-like trance as the hairpin was set in place for her.

“It suits you so well! Don’t you think so, too, mister?” the woman asked after fixing the hairpin to Sayo’s loosely tied hair.

“Yes, I think it’s lovely,” Rio agreed with a smile.

“T-Thank you very much! Really, Sir Rio.” Sayo finally returned to her senses and bobbed her head at Rio furiously.

“Not a problem. Shall we go, now? We still have other things to buy.” Rio shook his head, then suggested they went on their way. However, he suddenly remembered something, and asked the woman about kamutan.

“...Oh, that’s right. Miss, do you know of any good kamutan stores around here?”

“If it’s kamutan you’re after, then the food and dining stores are gathered toward that area over there. There’s a store called Kuma that’s quite reputable. It gets very crowded during lunch, so it’d be best to set aside some time when you go,” she replied, pointing toward the area where the restaurants were located.

“I see. Thank you very much.”

“Of course. I did sell something good, after all.” The merchant woman shook her head, then approached Sayo at a jog’s pace and whispered in her ear with a wink. “...Ah, Miss Sayo, wasn’t it? You have to do your best to win him over. This boy seems like quite the catch.”

“?!” Sayo looked down and flushed.

“Well, then! Please come again, if you ever have the chance to!” The merchant woman stepped away from Sayo and bid them farewell with a smile.

“Will do. Let’s go, Sayo.” Rio had been watching the two of them talk silently, but at the merchant woman’s farewell, he responded with a faint smile of his own. Then, he gestured at Sayo, and began walking.

Sayo started to walk after him, but turned back to bow at the merchant woman before she left. The woman waved with a smile.

There was a spring in Sayo’s steps as she hurried to catch up to Rio.

◇◇◇

After they ate kamutan at the store the merchant woman recommended, Rio and Sayo returned to the shopping district to resume their shopping for luxuries.

The main road had shops lining both sides, with a row of stalls down the middle that split the road into two. With plenty of pedestrian traffic, the road was crowded with the bustle of all kinds of people. Among them, Rio and Sayo were allowing the crowd to sweep them along, looking at the stores as they walked by them.

“T-There are even more people now.”

“It’s past noon, after all. More people are coming out after eating lunch. If you see a good store, let’s go inside.” They spoke as they walked, when...

“How dare you!” an angry voice yelled.

“Kya!” Sayo’s timid frame trembled with a flinch.

After a moment, confused voices began to stir around them.

“What? What is it?”

“Is it a fight? What’s going on?”

“Damn, I can’t see.”

“Hey, it looks like the mercenaries are messing with a woman and her kid.”

“No way!”

And so on. The chatter grew louder.

Rio enhanced his hearing ability with spirit arts to pick up on fragments of the conversation, before he heard angry voices from down the road once again.

“Insolent brat! Watch where you’re walking!”

“The rude one here is you, mere mercenary! Just who do you think you’re addressing?!” It seemed like a man and woman were arguing; a man’s gruff yelling voice and a woman’s dignified but enraged voice could be heard in that order. Following the outburst, from the same direction of the argument, a girl’s cute voice could be heard.

“Kya?!”

And then, after a beat: “What are you doing?!”

“Lady Komomo!”

“Oi, wait!” the woman’s uneasy voice said. It seemed as though the situation was turning into a crisis, but Rio couldn’t see anything from where he was.

“Move it!” A man’s voice could be heard some distance away; the crowd standing before Rio suddenly parted down the middle. Down that newly-made path a single mercenary-like man came running. He held a dagger in his right hand and a young girl tucked under his left arm as he ran, all the while threatening those who were in his way. The girl was unconscious, her head loosely hanging down.

“Move! Move it!” The man yelled in anger.

“Ah...” Perhaps she feared the man approaching her from the front, as Sayo stood still, unable to move. She had just been assaulted by Gon a few days prior, so her reaction was understandable.

“Tch.” The approaching man saw Rio and Sayo standing still in his path, and clicked his tongue. He decided to disregard them, and charge ahead anyway. However, without drawing his sword from the sheath at his waist, Rio leaped out in front, empty-handed. He then braced himself ready to receive the man’s body, unarmed.

At first, he dodged the man’s hand, which held a thrust-out dagger. Then, he skillfully knocked the man’s feet out from underneath him; his body spun once in the air. The man looked dazed.

Rio grabbed the girl from under the man’s arm and brought her closer to him, tucking her under his arm instead and driving his fist into the man’s solar plexus at the same time. Immediately, the man’s body collapsed on the ground.

“Guh...” The man let go of the dagger and slumped over, unconscious. It was all over in a flash.

“W... Woooooo!” The crowd was stunned for a moment, before they burst into cheers.

Looks of admiration were thrown in Rio’s direction; he gave a forced smile and ignored the attention, checking on the girl under his arm instead.

The girl was still young — around ten years old, it seemed. Her face was extremely refined, making her a very cute girl indeed.

She’s just knocked out. Either took a blow that knocked her out, or she was drugged into this state. Or, maybe it was done with sleeping spirit arts...

Rio briefly searched the flow of essence within the girl’s body and found no traces of tampering, so he decided it was most likely one of the first two options. Just in case she had been drugged, he cast a detoxifying spirit art as well.

There should be no fear for her life, now, at least. Next is...

After taking the necessary precautions with the girl, Rio glanced over at Sayo, who was staring blankly at him.

“Sayo. Are you all right?” Rio asked with a slightly awkward smile.

“Y-Yes! I’m fine.” Sayo returned to her senses and nodded furiously.

“Lady Komomo?!”

A woman appeared — she saw Rio carrying the girl named Komomo, with the sight of the kidnapper collapsed on the ground next to him, and immediately understood what was going on. She ran over to Rio in a hurry, and Rio offered the girl he was carrying in his arms to the woman.

“Here you go. She’s been knocked out, but her life shouldn’t be in danger.”

“I-I am sorry for the trouble. Thank you very much. If only I were more capable...” The woman took Komomo and bowed her head with a regretful expression.

“If you want to apologize to someone, save it for that girl when she wakes up. This man is unconscious right now... What would you like to do?” Rio asked. He shook his head and picked up the man’s dagger from the ground and held it out to the woman.

Chapter 7: To The Village

The day after his secret meeting with Homura and Shizuku, Rio departed from the capital alone. Gouki had adamantly proposed to send him off, but Rio had declined, saying he wanted to get back as soon as possible. In reality, what was several days’ journey on foot only took Rio one flight with his spirit arts.

“Welcome back,” the villagers said warmly as Rio returned to the village.

He responded to the villagers he met in kind. “I’m back,” he greeted them.

“I’m home,” Rio said as he entered the village chief’s house.

“Welcome home, Rio.” Yuba welcomed him cheerily from where she sat on a mat in the living room. “It seems like you managed to get some proper talks done.”

“Yes,” Rio nodded, smiling without realizing it. He was happy to see that Yuba’s attitude hadn’t changed.

“Shall I speak more formally when we’re alone together?” Yuba asked in jest, to which Rio rejected with a bitter smile.

“Please don’t.”

Yuba cackled with laughter. “Like I said before, even if you might be royalty, you and I will always be grandmother and grandson. That’s what I believe. As long as you think so, too, that will never change.”

“Thank you very much. Actually, there was something I wanted to consult with you regarding family...” Rio brought up questioningly.

“What’s this? You’re being all stiff.”

“It’s about Ruri. I’ve received permission to reveal my heritage to her, but I wanted to get your permission too...”

“...As long as she is related to you by blood, she has a right to know,” Yuba nodded with a huff of laughter.

“Thank you. Where might Ruri be now?”

“Having tea with the other village girls, I suppose. If she heard that you’ve returned, she’ll probably come running any moment now. She was worried when you suddenly left the village.”

“Is that so...” Rio smiled shyly.

That was when Ruri returned. “I’m home! Rio, you’re back! Geez, where did you go?!”

“I had some important matters to attend to. I’m sorry for making you worry.”

“Honestly. Granny wouldn’t even explain what happened when I asked her. You were suddenly taken away from the village by some strange people, so I was really worried.”

“There’s actually something I wanted to tell you about that...”

“Something to tell me?”

“Yes. But before I can tell you, you must agree to keep the details of this a secret.”

“Uhh, what’s this about?” Ruri tilted her head at Rio’s vague explanation.

“It’s about who I am. Yuba is already aware — that is why she let me live in this house. I would like you to know, too, but the secret has to be kept under strict confidentiality, so I wanted to check if you were okay with that first...” Rio chose his words carefully as he explained, peering at Ruri’s face.

“About who you are, huh? Yeah, I want to know. I promise, I won’t tell anyone what you tell me.” Ruri’s face was tinged with fear, but she nodded resolutely.

“Then, here goes.”

“Okay. Whenever you’re ready.” Ruri took a deep breath and nodded, waiting for Rio’s story to start. Rio exchanged glances with Yuba before opening his mouth somewhat nervously.

“First of all, you and I are cousins. My father was your father’s little brother.”

“...Huh. Is that so... You and I are cousins.”

While Ruri had stiffened slightly at the words, she accepted the truth offered to her rather readily.

“You don’t seem surprised...?” Yuba asked with wide eyes.

“...No, I am surprised, but I figured it’d be something like this based on the atmosphere in the room. And, Rio’s already family anyway.”

“Thank you,” Rio thanked her shyly. “I also think of you like family, which is why I wanted to bring this topic up. I wanted to tell you.”

“Y-Yeah, same here. Thank you.” Ruri, embarrassed, also offered her thanks.

“And so, my father... the person who would be your uncle, his name is Zen. My mother’s name is Karasuki. Karasuki Ayame. A princess of this kingdom.”

After a few long seconds of silence, Ruri cocked her head. “...Excuse me?”

“My mother was a princess of this kingdom,” Rio repeated with a wry smile.

“Guess this one’s a little harder to believe,” Yuba said with a hearty laugh.

“Umm... That’s a joke, right?”

“It’s the truth. Rio’s father... Your uncle... Married the princess of this kingdom.”

“Really, Granny?”

“I’m telling you, it’s the truth. Why would we lie about this?” Yuba nodded with a strained smile at Ruri’s still-dazed question.

“But... It’s just... ...Huuuh? Really? But then... Oh, no. That would... like, you know... That would make Rio a prince, right?”

“Well... I guess it would. Though unauthorized, Rio would be royalty of this kingdom.”

“Ahaha... But like, that’s still impossible. There’s no way a villager could marry a princess, after all.”

“Silly. Rio’s father was promoted to the status of a warrior for his distinguished service in the war. That was how he came to know Princess Ayame. I’d tell you to ask the others in the village... but you obviously can’t, although the older folks in the village know that Zen became a warrior.”

“A warrior... Then it wouldn’t have been odd for him to become acquainted with the princess, I guess? But then that would make Rio truly... a prince of this kingdom... right?”

“Lineage-wise, yes. That’s what I’ve been trying to tell you,” Yuba said with a tired sigh.

Ruri looked between Yuba and Rio’s face numerous times before finally coming to terms with what she had been told. Ruri paled as she suddenly turned to Rio and prostrated herself before him in a flurry. “E-Erm, P-Prince Rio... I-I’m so very sorry! Please forgive me for overstepping my boundaries and acting so rudely to you until now!”

“Wait! Please don’t do that. Just act like how you have been until now!” Rio stopped Ruri in a panic.

“B-But... Prince Rio is royalty... right?” Ruri raised her head at Rio timidly.

“My mother may have been, but I’m not. Even if you were to argue with the reasoning that the child of royalty must also be royalty, my existence can’t be made public. So, please. Just interact with me as you have been.” Rio shook his head bluntly, then bowed his head at Ruri.

“I can just... call you Rio?”

“Yes, that’s fine. Just like before.”

“I-I understand...” Ruri somehow managed to agree, but she was clearly still nervous.

“Your speech hasn’t changed back yet, you know?” Rio pointed out teasingly.

“Ah, yes... Right.” Ruri had almost unintentionally responded in the same stiff speech, when she managed to stop her thoughts and nod once more with an uncomfortable smile.

“I know you must be troubled to suddenly hear that I’m your cousin, but let’s please continue to get along.”

“...Yeah. I see... That’s right, Rio and I are cousins now,” Ruri muttered in a daze, as though reconfirming the truth. The impact of Rio’s mother being a princess was so powerful that she had completely forgotten the fact Rio was her own cousin.

“That’s right. I’m your cousin,” Rio said.

“So I still had blood relatives other than Granny. Ah, that means I’m an older sister to you by a year, right?”

“That would be correct. Would you like me to refer to you as my older sister?” Rio asked with a playful laugh.

“N-No, that’s fine! I’m sorry! Wow, that’s embarrassing! No way!” Ruri yelled with a bright red face.

“Then I’ll continue to call you Ruri like I have been,” Rio said, the corners of his lips turning up into a happy smile. Ruri’s expression wasn’t quite as accepting, though. “Mm. But we’re cousins, so... I think I’d prefer it if you spoke to me a bit more casually. Like a friendlier style of speech, no?” she asked, peering at Rio’s face.

“Umm. I’ve said this once before, but this speech is practically a habit of mine now. It’s just... once I’ve started using this speech, it’s difficult to switch without a significant reason to,” Rio explained with a troubled smile. Even if the other person was a child, as long as they weren’t arrogant, Rio was uncomfortable speaking too casually with someone he was meeting for the first time. Of course, once he had gotten closer, he was willing to speak without reservation. But, unless there was some sort of cue to do otherwise, he would keep using his stiff speech out of embarrassment.

“Hmph. So you’re saying that being my cousin isn’t a significant enough reason?” Ruri glared at Rio in a slightly sulking manner.

With that, Rio finally seemed to get the idea. “...Well, I guess, that would be correct. I’m sorry... Yep, you’re right. How about this?” he said shyly, averting his eyes out of embarrassment.

“Yup!” Ruri’s expression brightened cheerfully. Perhaps some of Rio’s somewhat uneasy awkwardness had gotten through to her, as she was unbearably happy, now.

After that, Rio told Ruri other necessary information — mostly regarding the reason why Zen and Ayame left the village and the circumstances behind it — and an explanation as to why Ruri needed to stay silent about Rio’s heritage to the other villagers. Ruri seemed to have some thoughts about Rio’s past, but she vowed to keep her silence.

Then, after Rio finished explaining his heritage to Ruri, he adjusted his posture and carefully looked at both her and Yuba.

“Also, this may be a little early, but I wanted to take this opportunity to inform the two of you of something.” Rio adjusted his posture and looked at the two of them.

“What’s this about?” Yuba asked.

“I’m thinking of leaving the village by this time next year,” Rio said, cutting straight to the point.

“I see... It’s a little sad, but it is what it is. Will you be returning to the land where you were born?” Yuba asked with a smile filled with loneliness.

“That’s right. There are many other places I want to stop by first, but eventually...” Rio confirmed with resolution in his eyes.

“You’ll come to this village again someday, right? This isn’t goodbye forever, is it?” Ruri, who had been listening silently, asked as she watched Rio’s face. “...That’s... Yeah. I’d like to come back, if you’d have me.” Rio smiled, somewhat troubled, as he nodded with hesitation.

“Of course we’d love to have you! What are you saying?!”

“That’s right — come back anytime. This is your hometown, too, and you are a member of our village.”

Ruri and Yuba both responded immediately, inviting Rio back. Rio thanked them both, happy to hear their reply.

“By the way, if there’s somewhere you have to go, does that mean there’s someone waiting for you there? If so, I’d like to hear about it. Won’t you tell us?” Ruri asked, curious.

“...While we’re not related by blood, there’s a child who thinks of me as an older brother, and a few other people who took care of me,” Rio answered a little shyly.

“Huh, so there are people like that. Is the one who treats you like a brother a little girl?”

“Well, yeah...”

“Heh, figures. But, well, if that’s the case, then we can’t keep you here forever. If she’s a little sister to you, then she’d be my cousin, too, so introduce her to me someday. Hey, tell me her name!” Ruri asked one question after another.

Chapter 9: Omens of Farewell

Winter came to an end, making way for spring to come to the village.

In that time, Rio had gone to Homura and Shizuku to give them his greetings for the new year, then returned from the capital with Komomo and Aoi. After returning to the village, he threw himself into the tasks of installing the water wheel and waterway, aiming to complete its construction for the spring.

At present, the water wheel was in operation, drawing the necessary amount of water and passing it through the waterway to supply the fields. Furthermore, Yuba lent Rio one of the village’s fields, and he began to take control of the farming there. He was requested to do so because the water wheel and waterway worked better than expected, causing an increase in the predicted harvest. Komomo and Aoi also offered to help; starting with Ruri and Sayo, several other villagers allocated their time to helping Rio.

At the moment, they were planting the seeds.

“Rio! I’m done planting the seeds in the area I was assigned!”

“Thanks. Can you help the people who haven’t finished yet?”

“Sure thing!”

The sound of the two people conversing at a slight distance echoed through the surroundings.

“Sir Rio, Aoi and I have finished our assigned area!” Komomo also energetically announced the completion of her quota.

“Thank you very much. You can rest for a bit, Komomo.”

Rio tried to be considerate of Komomo and Aoi, but Komomo shook her head enthusiastically. “I’m fine! I’ll help the other people too!”

“Hey, Rio! Why are you treating her differently than me?” Ruri pretended to sulk.

“No, it’s just... Komomo is a guest,” Rio excused with a wry smile.

“Rio, Ruri’s going to step all over you at this rate,” one of the working villagers interjected teasingly.

“Hey, I wouldn’t do such a thing!” Ruri argued with puffed cheeks.

That caused the other workers present to burst into hearty laughter. “Wahaha!”

Lately, Rio, Ruri, and Komomo had many more chances to be together as a group of three, so the villagers had become used to treating them as a three-person set. Furthermore, unbeknownst to the three in question, some people were gossiping that Rio was engaged to Komomo and Ruri as though it was fact.

Ruri was the only one Rio loosened his tone of speech around, and Komomo had been saved from danger by Rio before coming to stay at the village and sticking by his side around the clock, so their misunderstanding was understandable.

As a result, most of the girls that had secretly — or, rather openly — pined after Rio had given up on the fight, choosing to watch over the future of the three with warm eyes instead.

However, there were still some girls who hadn’t given up yet, and they continued to struggle in anguish.

The three of them look so close... How nice... Sayo watched the sight of Rio and the others from a distance with jealousy.

These days, Sayo hadn’t been able to find any time to talk with Rio properly, so seeing Ruri and Komomo working intimately with Rio made her feel extremely jealous. It was during this time that Rio took charge of one of the village fields and the helpers it required, so when Sayo heard about it, she couldn’t resist nominating herself.

However, Ruri and Komomo were still right by Rio’s side, and shy Sayo didn’t have the courage to close the distance between them.

“Shall I give you a hand, Sayo?”

Rio appeared before Sayo as she relentlessly planted seeds.

“Eh, ah, Sir Rio! I-I’m sorry! I was daydreaming!” Sayo stammered, snapping back to her senses. When she looked around at her surroundings, she saw it was clear that only her work was notably slower than everyone else’s. When she realized that, her faintly sunburned white cheeks reddened.

“Make sure you remember how to do all of this, Sayo. After I’m gone from the village, you may need to teach the other villagers what I’ve taught you. Well... Only if the results are good, that is.” Rio hinted to his departure from the village, gauging Sayo’s reaction.

“...Huh? Sir Rio, are you leaving the village?” Sayo asked with a dazed look.

“Yes. I haven’t told anyone else yet, but I’m thinking of leaving between next fall and winter.” Rio nodded with a somewhat wistful smile.

“Next... fall... Right, that’s right. You’re leaving. ...B-But, where will you go? If it’s nearby, you could still come visit the village every now and then!” Sayo asked dumbfoundedly, clinging to a sliver of hope.

Rio shook his head regretfully. “I plan on crossing kingdom borders and traveling far away, so I can’t guarantee I’ll be able to periodically return. But I do want to visit the village again.”

“But...” Sayo said in a trailing voice.

“It’s still a little early, but I wanted to let you know ahead of time. We haven’t really had the chance to talk to each other lately, and I’ve been having trouble coming to a decision, too...”

As Rio spoke about his feelings — “Nnh...”

Sayo was on the verge of tears before she knew it. When she noticed that tears were threatening to spill over, she ducked her head in a panic and rubbed her eyes.

“What’s wrong, Sayo?”

“Ah, no, nothing! It’s nothing! Just some dirt that got into my eye... Ah, I see now. There’s soil on my hands.” Sayo laughed with all her might and closed her eyes.

“Erm, I’ll make some water with spirit arts. You can duck your head and wash it out.” Rio tilted his head in slight suspicion, but chose to believe Sayo’s words and created a small bubble of water in his hand, manipulating it to float gently near her eyes.

Sayo thrust her face into the bubble and blinked rapidly. Not wanting Rio to realize she had been crying, she flushed her eyes with enough water to make them appear bloodshot.

“Ahaha. I’m sorry for such a shameful sight to see.”

“No, it’s fine... Do your eyes hurt?” Rio asked, voicing his concern for her.

“I’m fine! I’ll do my best to make up for where I fell behind!” Sayo shrugged him off with forced cheeriness. That was when Ruri arrived.

“Sayo, what’s wrong?”

“Ah, Ruri. Some dirt got in my eye, so Sir Rio was helping me rinse it out.”

“Aah, I see...” It wasn’t such a rare occurrence when working with soil, so Ruri accepted her words without question.

“Umm, I fell behind in my share of work, so I’m going to get back to that now.”

“Oh, I’ll help you.”

With that, Sayo returned to her seed-planting work with a look of enthusiasm and Ruri at her heels. Sayo devoted herself to the work at hand, because she knew she would burst into tears if she didn’t. Then, once work was over for the day, Rio thanked the villagers that assisted him.

“Good work, everyone! Thanks to your hard work, we were able to complete our target workload. Don’t forget what I taught you today — you’ll need to plant the seeds in the same way next year.”

It was already evening, so everyone split up and went their own way home. Among them were Ruri and Komomo, who called out to Rio energetically.

“Rio, good work! Let’s go home too?”

“There’s a lot more to planting seeds than I thought, Sir Rio. I can train in a different way to my usual practice with this!”

The three people living underneath the one roof — four people if Komomo’s personal attendant, Aoi, was included — naturally went home together. Meanwhile, Sayo watched them absentmindedly from a short distance away, before walking toward her own home in the opposite direction. Her mood was strangely dark, enough to make the villagers she passed hesitate in greeting her. Once she arrived home, the strength drained from Sayo’s knees as she sat down just inside the door on the clay floor.

“...”

She curled up and let the tears gush forth like a broken dam.

“I’m ho... H-Hey, Sayo?!” Shin arrived at the front door in a fluster, and his eyes widened at the sight of Sayo crying on the clay floor. She noticed Shin and raised her saddened eyes.

“What’s wrong?! Did something happen?”

“...Shin. I’m sorry. I’m fine... It’s nothing. I’ll go make dinner now.” Sayo shook her head weakly and staggered to her feet.

“This isn’t the time to be making food! Who was it? Who made you cry?!” Shin asked as he breathed heavily through his nose, desperately trying to think of the reason behind Sayo’s tears.

The first thing that came to his mind was Rio.

Vexing as it was to admit, the only person who could upset Sayo’s emotions this much was him. The biggest proof of that was how Sayo was clutching the hairpin she received from Rio tightly in her hand.

“That asshole... Rio must have done something.”

Shin decided there could be no one else who would have made Sayo cry.

“N-No... It’s not... Sir Rio’s fault...” Hearing Shin’s voice trembling with anger made Sayo explain herself in a panic, but she couldn’t speak all that well, as she was overcome with tears. Seeing his sister like that made the fury within Shin boil over even more.

“That guy should have never come to this village.” Even as he said those words, Shin knew in the back of his mind that it wasn’t right.

Thanks to Rio’s contributions in the village, their lives had definitely gotten better, and if Rio hadn’t been here, Ruri and Sayo would’ve suffered greatly at the hands of Gon.

Because of that, he had secretly accepted Rio’s existence in the village.

Seeing the sight of his sister crying before him, however, made him doubt if it would have been better if Rio hadn’t come to the village at all. If he hadn’t, then at least Sayo wouldn’t be crying right now.

“No, you’re wrong... Sir Rio is going to leave the village... That’s why...” Sayo desperately tried to stand up for Rio’s innocence.

“...What did you say? He’s leaving the village?” Shin frowned greatly at that.

“No, Sir Rio doesn’t have anything to do with it...” Sayo tried to emphasize Rio’s irrelevance to her current disposition, but it was already too late.

“He’s going to leave the village... So that’s why!” Once Shin connected the dots, a sour expression took over his face.

It was true that Rio was originally an outsider; he came to this village during his travels, so it made sense for him to leave on another journey. But, that meant Sayo would keep crying.

What could he do? How could he stop Sayo’s tears?

Shin desperately tried to think things through, but he wasn’t the type of person who solved things with his head. Shin knew that better than anyone.

That was why thinking made him lose his cool and rush out of the house instead. Rather than thinking about it any further, he’d act on his instincts.

“Eh?! S-Shin?! W-Wait!” He could hear Sayo’s voice try to stop him from behind, but he paid her no mind as he ran with all his might. He made a beeline straight for Yuba’s house.

“Oi, Rio! Is Rio here?!” Shin burst through the front door with a burning face, yelling for Rio. Rio and the others, who had been preparing for dinner, widened their eyes in surprise at the sudden appearance.

“...What do you want with Rio?” Yuba questioned with a suspicious look.

It was fairly rare for Shin to have business with Rio to begin with, but his desperate expression showed it was no trivial matter. Just what could it be about?

“Please, stay in the village!” Shin said, and knelt on the ground.

“Wha...?!” Rio and the others were all rendered speechless at Shin’s truly sudden, erratic behavior.

“I-I know I’m being selfish with this request! But, please, hear me out for a moment. Could you stay in the village forever?!”

Sayo was crying — Shin wasn’t able to say those words out loud, so he rubbed his forehead against the ground instead. Rio and the others were dumbfounded and rendered unable to speak.

It was then that Sayo suddenly appeared, panting for breath.

“S-Shin! What are you doing?! I-I’m sorry that my brother has caused you so much trouble!” Her eyes rounded at the sight of Shin bowed on the ground, before she lowered her head in a panicked apology.

“But... Sayo—” Shin began to say something unpleasantly.

“C-Come on, Shin. You’re being such a bother. Let’s go, okay?” Sayo pulled at Shin’s body frantically.

“...” Shin glanced over at Sayo’s face to see her fake smile; there were traces of tears at the corners of her eye. While her tone was gentle, her urgency clearly shone through. “A-All right... Sorry.” Shin lifted his body up sluggishly.

“I’m truly so sorry! I’ll give my brother a stern talking to!” Sayo promptly apologized with her head bowed.

“S-Sorry...” Shin awkwardly lowered his head.

“...Okay. We won’t ask what that was about for now. Is that all right, Rio?” Yuba asked, sighing tiredly.

“Sure, I don’t mind...” Rio nodded, looking over at Sayo and Shin inquiringly.

Stay in the village... That’s because of what I told Sayo about today, right? But why would Shin come to me... Rio tried to think of the intention behind Shin’s actions, but he couldn’t understand the heart of another.

At any rate, he couldn’t bear the sight of Shin and Sayo both lowering their heads at him.

“T-Thank you very much! Come on, let’s go, Shin.” Sayo thanked them in relief and dragged Shin away. The silence continued for several moments after their departure.

“Lady Komomo, Miss Aoi, I apologize on the behalf of our villagers. Shall we have our meal, now? Ruri, get to cooking,” Yuba said to dispel the mood.

Thus, everyone exchanged a look before nervously resuming their actions. Though they didn’t talk about what had just happened, the uncomfortable atmosphere continued into supper.

◇◇◇

After dinner, when everyone had retired for the night, Yuba visited Rio’s room.

“Rio, are you still awake?”

“Yes, I’m awake.”

The question had come from just outside his door, so Rio replied in a quiet voice.

“I’m coming in.”

“Go ahead.”

Rio stood up from his bed and opened the door to welcome Yuba inside. He pulled up a cushion for Yuba to sit on as he sat down on his own bed.

“...Did you tell Sayo?” After several seconds of silence, Yuba suddenly charged straight into the core of the matter. She chose not to specify what they talked about on purpose.

“Yes. I did.”

“I see. Then, do you know the reason as to why Shin acted that way?”

“...I’m sorry. To be honest, I have no idea. Do you know, Yuba?” Rio shook his head apologetically, fearfully asking back.

“Probably... However, it is not something that should come out of my mouth. The people in question wouldn’t want that, after all. It would not be right of me.”

“...I see.”

“The only thing I can tell you is that this incident is not your fault, so there’s no need to blame yourself for any reason. Understand?” Yuba warned at Rio’s shamed nod.

“That’s...” Rio’s expression darkened as he avoided answering.

“Well, I know that just telling you this won’t ease your worries. Could I ask you to trust your grandmother this once, and leave this situation to me?”

“Yuba...”

“Though, there’s not much I can do. I’ll try to talk to those two indirectly about it. For now, could you interact with them without prying too much into it? Of course, if they choose to make the first step, then I would want you to engage with them about it,” Yuba said with a light shrug.

“I understand. I’m sorry for making you bear the burden...”

“It’s fine — try relying on your family a little more. You’re saddled with enough to begin with.”

“...Yes.” Yuba’s words must have reached him, as Rio hung his head when he nodded.

◇◇◇

After that incident, they returned to what seemed like peaceful days on the surface. Since they often saw each other during the hunt, Rio had to face Shin sooner rather than later.

“Sorry for the other day... But, could you give us a little more time? For me, and for Sayo. You might have no idea what I’m talking about, but it isn’t the right time to give you an explanation yet... Though I may bring it up again one day,” Shin said awkwardly, his expression strangely serious for once.

“I understand. I intend on leaving the village before next winter, just so you know.”

Rio widened his eyes at the admirable attitude that Shin normally didn’t show. He recalled the words Yuba said to him, and decided to wait patiently for their reply until he had to leave the village.

Thus, he was able to return to a normal relationship with Shin relatively easily, but the harder one to repair was his relationship was Sayo. Of course, they still spoke to each other when they were working in the village together, and it wasn’t as though they were acting distant with each other on the surface, but the amount of time he had to speak with Sayo when they were alone definitely decreased.

In effect, it became nonexistent.

It seemed that Sayo was the one who was intentionally keeping her distance from Rio. Because of that, Sayo’s position in the three-person group she used to form with Ruri and Rio had become completely replaced with Komomo instead.

Other than the times Komomo returned to the capital with Rio on his visits to Homura and Shizuku, she was practically always in the village. Other members of the Saga family would also drop by whenever they had the time, completely adapting themselves to the village lifestyle. By the time summer had arrived, they could even be found carrying a hoe rather than a sword.

Once summer came around, Rio informed the other villagers that he officially intended to leave sometime in the days after the autumn harvest festival. The villagers were extremely saddened by the news, but they set about preparing for the harvest festival with even more vigor now that it included Rio’s farewell party.

Thus, the seasons passed by in the blink of an eye, and finally fall arrived.

Afterword

Hello, everyone — This is Yuuri Kitayama. Thank you very much for picking up Requiem for a Goodbye.

It’s been half a year since Seirei Gensouki Volume 1 first came out, and it feels like Volume 3 was released in the blink of an eye. In that time, Volume 1 received two additional printings. I can’t even express how grateful I am to all the readers, Hobby Japan, and everyone else involved in the process.

And so, to begin with, I’d like to acknowledge everyone I am much indebted to!

The readers who always support my work; Editor N and the other editors at HJ Bunko; Riv, who drew so many beautiful, high-quality illustrations this volume too; the publishing sales department at Hobby Japan; the thorough and detailed proofreaders; each bookstore with my work on their shelves, and so on. Thank you very much! This book wouldn’t have existed without the help of each and every one of you.

As I am still an inexperienced author only freshly debuted, there is still much knowledge that I am lacking, and I may make mistakes here and there, but I’ll continue to work diligently, so I hope that you can stick with me for a long time to come.

Now, to change the topic suddenly due to lack of page space, Volumes 1 to 3 of this Seirei Gensouki series are actually a prologue, so to speak, and with the end of this volume, the main character Rio (Haruto) finally reaches the starting line of the story.

Normally, stories start from the first volume, with the main character having built a number of relationships and an established past. However, even before I made the plot of Seirei Gensouki, the first time I thought of writing a novel, I thought that having such backstories depicted in the story would make the later plot more interesting.

However, the darker sides of those stories are unavoidable, and sometimes make it difficult to act out a clear sense of exhilaration. At the same time, that is what will make future volumes more interesting, slowly and steadily — or, sometimes, all at once.

Finally, Seirei Gensouki has built up a reputation of increasing the number of pages as the volume number goes up, but I will try to make the next volume slightly more compact.

No, I will definitely do it!

Let’s meet again in the next volume.

January 2016 Yuuri Kitayama